# Manuel Sainsily

## **Currently XR Design Manager - Unity Technologies**

I manage a team of ten senior designers and researchers on the topics of User eXperience (UX), Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) and eXtended Reality (XR). We use human-centred design to create products, services, and experiences that improve the lives of millions of people.

### Recent Experiences

Sep 2019 - Jan 2021 Montreal, Canada

# Sr. UI/UX/XR Designer & Haptics Researcher - Immersion

I joined the Montreal research lab to help define the computerhuman interactions of tomorrow by growing the UX design philosophy within the company and our 150+ licensed clients, as well as helping increase the worldwide awareness around haptics (3+ Billion devices using our tech).

Apr 2017 - Aug 2019 Montreal, Canada

## Lead XR Design Canada - IBM

I worked at the intersection of progressive strategy, creative vision, and transformational technology, designing interactions across multiple digital channels for both consumers and employees alike.

I developed the Canadian Design practice around eXtended Realities (XR) and helped educate clients and employees from various industries.

May 2016 - Mar 2017 Montreal, Canada

# Lead UI/UX Designer - Fans Entertainment

I co-developed and maintained the Design System of www.golo.io, as well as the mobile apps and the CMS.

May 2014 - Apr 2016 Montreal, Canada

#### Lead UI/UX Designer - Mindgeek

I worked on the UI/UX & marketing campains of websites attracting a total of more than 100M daily users.

#### **Education**

Nov 2010 - Mar 2013 Nov 2008 - Jul 2010 Master of Science in Computer Sciences, SUPINFO Bachelor of Science in Computer Sciences, SUPINFO

#### **About**

Born in Guadeloupe Based in Montreal

#### Connect

https://manu.vision
manuel.sainsily@gmail.com